honestjohn.co.uk 2017-09-03

# Terms and Conditions | Honest John

**Privacy and cookie policy**

This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read this policy carefully before you use the site.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (Act), the data controller is HonestJohn.co.uk Ltd (we or us) of Eaglethorpe Barns, Warmington, Peterborough PE8 6TJ

Our nominated representative for the purpose of the Act is Nova J Robinson

It is very important to us that you should be able to use and enjoy the website without your privacy being compromised in any way. Please read the following to understand how your personal information will be treated. Please note that this policy may change from time to time as the website develops so please check back regularly. However, we will not reduce your rights under this privacy policy without your explicit consent. Any changes we make will be posted on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including but not limited to an email notification of privacy policy changes)

Please remember that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords. Please be careful and responsible when you're online.

Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site www.honestjohn.co.uk (site). This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by us, and when you report a problem with our site.

  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders.

  * Details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, and the resources that you access.

Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.

  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us

  * To assess the technical performance of our systems and to enhance service levels.

  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by [post or telephone].

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data.

We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that 500 men aged under 30 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in SW1). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience.]

We will not sell, rent, trade, share, reveal or disclose any of your personal information, unless

  * you have specifically requested that we do so;

  * we deem it necessary to provide you with services you have requested;

  * we are required to do so by a Court of competent jurisdiction or by a governmental order, decree, regulation or rule of any regulatory agency;

  * our terms and conditions state that we will;

  * we reasonably believe that use of disclosure is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to an individual's life, health or safety or a serious threat to public health or safety; or

  * we have reason to suspect that unlawful activity has been, is being or may be engaged in and the use or disclosure of your personal information is a necessary part of our investigation of the matter or in reporting our concerns to relevant persons or authorities.

We may provide aggregate information and statistics about HonestJohn.co.uk users, traffic patterns, and related site information to third parties, but these statistics will not include individual personal information.

Some of our products are hosted by third parties but we agree with those third parties that they will keep your information secure and not use it for other purposes.

If you sign up for services that are managed or offered by other organizations, they will obtain your information.

A number of other people's web sites have links on our site. If you link to their sites, they may collect information. Such sites are not within our control and are not covered by this privacy statement.

## IP addresses and Cookies

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. 

What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer browser from a website's computer and is stored on your computer's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other websites. Many websites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows.

What type of cookies do we use?

We use the following cookies: 

Strictly necessary cookies. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services. 

Analytical/performance cookies. They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily. 

Functionality cookies. These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

Targeting cookies. These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

How can cookies be managed/ blocked?

Users have the opportunity to set their devices to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these means that certain personalised features cannot then be provided to that user and accordingly they may not be able to take full advantage of all of the website's features. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. Alternatively, you may wish to visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org/](http://www.aboutcookies.org/), which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of desktop browsers.

During the course of any visit to our site, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your computer. Our site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site and also allows us to improve our site.

Third party cookies

Please note that third parties (including Yahoo and other advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies. 

To find out which third party cookies are stored on your PC and possibly to remove them, please visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/) to opt out.

Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a location outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 1985.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

  * If HonestJohn.co.uk Ltd or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of HonestJohn.co.uk Ltd our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at data@honestjohn.co.uk.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to privacy@honestjohn.co.uk.

HonestJohn.co.uk Limited, Wagstaffs, Richmond House, Walkern Rd, Stevenage SG1 3QP. Registered in London no 6011794.
